Soumya Veer

• San Mateo, CA • (832) 803-6200 • veer.soumya@gmail.com • github.com/soumyaveer • soumyathinks.com •

SUMMARY

An analytical, hard working web developer with a passion for learning. I am experienced in Ruby, JavaScript, SQL and have a background in Electrical Engineering. I want to use my problem-solving skills and technology to solve challenging problems.

SKILLS

Object oriented programming using Ruby and JavaScript. Ruby on Rails, Sinatra, React, SQL, HTML, CSS, Data Structures & Algorithms.

PROJECTS

Trivia Zone - https://github.com/soumyaveer/trivia-zone

Trivia Zone is a fun way to test your knowledge and compete with others online.

- Uses Ruby on Rails and Postgres on the backend.
- Uses JQuery, Bootstrap and custom CSS on the frontend.
- Uses Devise and OmniAuth for Facebook OAuth authentication.
- Deployed on Heroku.

Reminders - https://github.com/soumyaveer/reminders

This app helps you manage important tasks by scheduling them via email notifications.

- Uses Ruby on Rails as the backend API server.
- · Uses React, Redux, React Router on the frontend.
- Deployed on Heroku.

Book Progress - https://github.com/soumyaveer/book-progress

Book Progress helps you track your reading progress and watch what others are reading.

- Uses Sinatra and Postgres on the backend.
- Uses CSS, Bootstrap on the frontend.
- Uses a custom signup and authentication system written from scratch.
- Deployed on Heroku.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Math Tutor

University of Houston

June 2014—May 2015, Houston, Texas

Taught undergraduate students algebra, geometry, business calculus, and other Math related undergraduate courses.

Systems Engineer

Infosys, Ltd.

November 2009—October 2012, Pune, India

- Developed and automated the execution of SQL queries to generate billing reports.
- Worked to diagnose and fix bugs in one of the Bank of America applications.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School (on a scholarship from shegeeksout.com)

July 2017—April 2018

 8 month Fullstack Web Development program. The highlights of this program were: Ruby, Javascript, Rails, SQL, React, HTML, CSS, Data Structures & Algorithms.

University of Houston

August 2013-May 2015, Houston, Texas

• Degree: M.S. in Electrical Engineering. GPA 3.6

Visvesvaraya Technological University

August 2005-May 2009, Bangalore, India

• Degree: BE. in Electronics and Communications Engineering. GPA 3.6